please welcome AIP lead at palen here Jack
Dobson hello welcome to AIP con I'm Jack
Dobson AIP lead at palente and today I'm
excited to be presenting to you the next
generation of AIP and how it's transforming
end to-end operations for our customers every
pented deployment exists to drive operational
outcomes against our customers core Mission and
the critical role that they play in the world from
the factory floor to the hospital Ward and from
the battlefield to the boardroom that requires
an unwavering focus on empowering the operator at
the front line explicitly moving beyond analysis
and insight and instead owning the outcome of
every decision the Relentless pursuit of this
across our customers continues to expose where
the traditional software Playbook falls short
the market is saturated with light unopinionated
tooling thin wrappers on existing process that
provide Insight without action all forcing the
buyer to conform their business to the constraints
of their software AI Solutions have only further
cluttered the landscape with everything from
surface level chatbots to llm infr Solutions all
competing for their place in the architecture
diagram without any of them truly closing the
loop to decisions that impact the business pentes
customers sit at the bleeding edge they operate
in some of the most Mission critical sensitive
and competitive environments they therefore demand
more from the systems on which they build and run
their operations this ambition requires building
not just point Solutions or a set of use cases
but instead a connected operating system for the
Enterprise let's look at this from the perspective
of one company a notional organization called Onyx
Incorporated which represents the culmination of
hundreds of production AIP deployments globally
this notional Enterprise is a global Healthcare
manufacturer and distributor onyx's operations
are run on palen with ontology as the connective
tissue across all Enterprise context operational
logic and decisionmaking this enables workflows
that are incredibly rich and detailed integrating
down to the sensor level of every machine and the
raw materials behind every product this Foundation
is intrinsically cross domain every function of
the business operating on the same ground truth
enabling chained optimization like never before
most critical basically this Rich connected
ontology serves as a foundation for a new
approach to decision making core functions of
the business are now agent driven with human
operators refocused to only the most critical
complex and valuable of actions requiring their
involvement these agent-driven workflows span the
interconnected operations of Onyx Incorporated so
let's dive into one of these workflows in more
detail starting with order fulfillment this is
our inventory manager here I can monitor the
movement of every customer order through the
automated flow that takes orders through every
core stage of fulfillment from initial review
of the incoming order including attachments
comments and Communications from the customer
to allocation of inventory to every order and then
assigning of those orders to shipments optimizing
for ontime delivery and minimizing shipment costs
my automations are set up in a way that every new
order is worked on in parallel allowing hundreds
if not thousands of orders to be processed every
minute this human AI teeming is made possible by a
core principle of AIP that every primitive of the
ontology can be leveraged by both human operators
and AI agents jumping under the hood of this
workflow we see the circuitry of the ontology that
connects the context of my Enterprise the logic
of my business processes and the actions that
enact decisions these are the building blocks
of my Enterprise operating system with every
one of those building blocks a common interface
between human users and AI agents zooming in even
further we see how this operational layer is the
culmination of all existing components and systems
across my Enterprise wherever data and logic
sit in whatever form storage or compute aip's
multimodal data plane enables us to ingest or
virtualize it into the ontology as well as right
back to the systems of action that need to be
orchestrated to enact operator decisions this is
the core of palente platform enabling the building
of an ontology to drive decisionmaking at the
front line agnostic to the architecture that sits
beneath it whilst maintaining granular control of
permissions data health and change management so
how does this ontology Drive agent automation at
Onyx well let's look at one of the agents involved
in this process to see that in action this is AIP
logic an application for building evaluating and
deploying agents all built with the same building
blocks of the ontology logic allows me to serve
these Primitives to llms of my choice as tools
allowing us to automate the manual repetitive
workflows that draw my operator's time from the
actions uniquely requiring their expertise this
involves combining multiple llm blocks providing
llm of my choosing with the instructions the
context and the tools to drive decisions across
my ontology object query tools allow my agents
to reach out to specific parts of my ontology
to retrieve context relevant to their inputs
and the tasks that they're carrying out we also
provide action tools the very same actions that
a human operator would use to enact cisions logic
allows me to give those same actions to the llm
to use without any additional configuration
required to ready these tools for AI as we
further explore this inventory allocation agent
we see how these tools allow the agent to query
real-time inventory levels and even unstructured
documentation to identify relevant procedures
and Sops and our agents are built to reason and
solution adverse situations based on the logic
that I encode for example this agent has some
options for dealing with inventory shortages in
this case the agent has access to a function tool
to run an inventory reallocation model this will
scenario Model A movement of inventory from one
Distribution Center to another to see if there
will be any adverse Downstream effects based
on my order back log and my sales forecasts we
can also provide our agent with our product
documentation to determine whether a skew
substitution is possible to alleviate a shortage
what can and can't be automated can be controlled
granularly at the logic level but then also
part of the automation that defines when this
agent is triggered this automation provides me
with the controls over agent trigger criteria
as well as whether edits to the ontology can
be made or autonomously by the automation I
also have control over Dynamic retries and other
safety nets to ensure maximum reliability of my
in production agents with these granular controls
AI automation becomes a dial that I can tune up or
down depending on the maturity and the impact
of my workflow speaking of impr production as
we increase the breadth and depth of automation
across the Enterprise it's critical to maintain
visibility of how my agents are performing
for this we have AIP evals evals allow me to
set up any number of test cases and evaluators
against my logic everything from checking for
specific outputs to rubric graders where I can
use another llm as a judge to evaluate my logic
against a defined criteria and since changing
llms is as simple as a dropdown I can very
quickly run tests to see what combination of LMS
is optimal for each individual agent so we've seen
how agents have built tested and deployed let's
Zoom back out to our inventory manager workflow
to see how this enables my operators to work in
collaboration with my agents we can see all of
those customer orders have now been processed
with the majority being fulfilled autonomously
by my network of Agents but a subset have been
flaged for user action jumping in as the operator
I now have a full action log handled by the agent
I can see what data was accessed what tools were
used and how that all contributed to the agent's
final decision this becomes valuable context as I
pick up where the agent left off and take the
required actions to move this order forward I
now have a bespoke view in order to review an
action on the ERS being flagged by my agents I
can review agent proposals mitigating the need
for me to manually run through scenarios myself
and instead I can just review edit and feedback on
these proposed actions as needed and as the user
I can approve this recommendation to enact the
proposed actions and get this customer order back
in the agent orchestrated flow my actions are set
up to write back to my source systems my MRP my
production schedule and all relevant scenarios
keeping everything in sync for our customers
building with warp speed this is transforming how
they respond to rapidly changing supply and demand
and this decision doesn't just become exhaust Into
The Ether every response to an agent proposal is
captured in the ontology as shown previously the
same tools available to my agent to propose this
action are available to me as the operator to
take alternative action as I see fit including
triggering new purchase orders or alternative
allocations of inventory and I can also add
commentary on the agent specific working to call
out errors or maybe even add missing context that
may have materially impacted the decision here I'm
contributing back to the ontology in a way that
informs a feedback loop for this workflow based on
context that may not currently exist in any system
this tribal knowledge capture is now happening
continually across all workflows all of the
context the experience and the logic being
incorporated into decisions that lives only
in the minds of your operators you can now manage
it as a workflow not only tracking and reviewing
this context but deploying it back into your
workflows as a governed feedback loop so this
process has been redefined around human AI teaming
our operators working collaboratively with our AI
agents with actions and their outcomes continually
enriching the Enterprise context captured in the
ontology zooming out further we see this as
just a subset of the overall process we see
that every state change of the order fulfillment
process is not only tracked in the platform but
also augmented by AI agent automations as we
start chaining these agents together you're
establishing a limitlessly scalable AI labor that
can operate autonomously alongside other users
this becomes the foundations of the kinetics of my
business and this AI labor isn't just reactive to
triggers my agents can also proactively monitor
my assets to get ahead of potential risks to
my operations looking Upstream of fulfillment
now to manufacturing our maintenance workflow
centers around equipment failure risks generating
by an ml model running against live Telemetry from
our production Machinery we then have a similar
chained agent process as we saw in the previous
workflow but of course this one with brand new
agents specialized for getting ahead of this
event and preventing downtime our first agent is
regularly running this failure risk model against
all machines on all production lines globally this
model will take in realtime Telemetry from the
machine which we have flowing into the ontology
and run anomaly detection to identify the risk of
imminent failure this agent then chains multiple
Downstream models to contextualize and prioritize
this risk including calculating the maintenance
cost to repair the machine and the revenue loss if
the production line goes down these are powerful
models brought to the business by the ontology and
democratized to both human operators and AI agents
these agent identified failure risks then trigger
a dedicated agent chain for the process including
identifying a recommended solution for every alert
based on documentation historic maintenance and
of course our Enterprise feedback loop then we
have Dynamic scheduling for the maintenance to go
to an optimal technician based on skill set and
availability all of this dynamically prioritized
based on that calculated dollar risk of
the downtime the result of this chained agent flow
well now my technicians have their own dedicated
work cues geared towards providing operators with
all the context and the guidance to interpret and
action on issues quickly every machine is entirely
ontologized meaning each alert is tied to the
specific component I need to repair or replace
to prevent this predicted downtime leveraging
all of the context of the component's position in
the machine it's a Associated sensor data and of
course our maintenance history and then finally we
again have that opportunity to capture context and
the outcome of this maintenance action from the
field contributing back to our feedback loop and
leveling up this workflow with every work order
yet another workflow building on and contributing
back to our Enterprise operating system spanning
the full value chain of Onyx Incorporated
so to conclude the ontology enables a connected
operating system required by these institutions
operating at the bleeding edge it serves as
a common interface for both humans and AI
agents across all types of applications enabling
Enterprises to steadily and smoothly increase AI
driven automation redefining the operations
of the business as the world evolves around
it the infusion and scaling of AI should enable
organizations to better meet their core Ambitions
to remove latency between strategic shifts and
operational action and ultimately to optimally
deliver against the organization's mission in
whatever way that manifests thank you very much